Hello everyone and welcome to English Pod.
My name is Marco.
My name is Katherine and today
we're talking about a special kind of man.
That's right today we are, well everyone
starts living with your parents but as a
adult some people still want to
continue living with their parents.
That's right so the
topic of today's lesson is
living with your parents
when you're an adult.
Let's take a listen to the dialogue.
Why did your girlfriend break up with you?
I don't know. She said she was tired of me
not manning up and being more independent.
What do I think is all a bunch of crap?
Well you still live with your
parents so she does have a point.
What do you mean a lot of
people live with their parents,
especially when rent is so expensive
in the slump in the economy?
Yeah but you're almost 40 plus you make
good money so there's really no excuse.
It's just simply because
you're a mama's boy.
Whatever dude, I have everything I need.
Why would I move out?
I have a great roof over my head.
My mom does my laundry and cooks for me.
What else could a guy ask for?
Let's agree to disagree.
All right we're back so now let's take a
look at some language on language takeaway.
Language takeaway.
The first verb we have here
is to break up so we heard
the guy say why did your
girlfriend break up with you?
That's right so this is a phrasal
verb and to break up in a
relationship or in a romantic
sense means to end a relationship.
So if you break up with your girlfriend
it means you end the relationship.
That's right so you think about
breaking something, it goes into pieces.
Well in a relationship it means you
both leave each other, you go your
separate ways and so you can say
he broke up with me or we broke up.
That's right and the reason his
girlfriend broke up with him is because
she said he was not independent so
she wanted him to be more independent.
So independent means that you do
things on your own when you're you
know you do things alone you
don't expect other people to help you.
You don't depend on other people.
Exactly so you can say he's very
independent he loves to travel alone.
Okay so it means that you don't really
need other people's help I guess right?
Exactly okay all right so he's
not really very independent
and well his friend agrees
he says well you know what?
I think she has a point
to have a point means to
say something that the
other person agrees with.
Okay so you could say he has a point I
agree with him that's a good argument.
Right so if you if somebody says something
and you agree with that when you say yeah you
have a point it means you agree with the
argument you agree with what that person says.
All right and now lastly because
he lives with his parents his
friend is saying that he should
move out you should move out.
So here's another phrasal
verb to move out this means
that you leave the house
and you find a new house.
So when you're with your parents
you want to move out that means you
don't live with your parents
anymore but you find your own house.
That's right so well in general
when you find your own house when
you leave in your current place
of living that's moving out right.
That's right so if I'm leaving
the city I move out of my house
and then when I arrive in a new
city I move in to a new house.
Very good so to move out and to
move in they go hand in hand. All right so
let's listen to the dialogue again
and we'll be back with Fluency Builder.
Why did your girlfriend
break up with you?
I don't know she said
she was tired of me not
manning up and being more independent
which I think is all a bunch of crap.
Well you still live with your
parents so she does have a point.
What do you mean a lot
of people live with their
parents especially
when rent is so expensive
in the slump in the economy?
Yeah but you're almost
40 plus you make good money
so there's really no excuse.
It's just simply because
you're a mama's boy.
Whatever dude I
have everything I need.
Why would I move out?
Have a great roof over my
head my mom does my
laundry and cooks for me.
What else could a guy ask for?
Let's agree to disagree.
All right so now four phrases for
you on Fluency Builder. Fluency Builder.
So you've got a very
interesting phrase here
at the beginning of
Fluency Builder today.
The phrase is manning up so the girlfriend
was tired of the man not manning up.
Right so two man up and what does
that mean to man up to something?
It means to be responsible
or to be more mature or
to be an adult about
something so maybe this guy
this man he's kind of
immature. That's right.
He lives at home he's not
very responsible or independent
and his girlfriend wanted
him to be more responsible,
more independent so
she wanted him to man up.
That's right so usually
means that you also should
accept the consequences
for your actions right?
Exactly so you might push
someone to man up take
responsibility for something
and do it even though
the consequences
might not be fun or good.
Now this remember is very
very much slang so you don't
say this in an essay or
a paper. This is what you
say between friends. And
another slang phrase here
that we used to describe
this man is a mama's boy.
He says his friend
says he's a mama's boy.
Mama's boy so mama is
mother. Mama's boy means
that he's very very
close with his mother.
This is not a good thing to say it's usually
something that's a little bit critical.
Okay so he's a mama's
boy. It's mother washes his
clothes, she cooks his
food, she does everything
for him and he doesn't
do anything for himself.
He's like a little baby.
He's like a child and
his mama, his mother
does everything for him.
So it is a little bit
like an insult I guess.
Okay so it's not really
a good thing to call
someone a mama's boy
unless in this situation
their friends and his
friend is saying well
you know what it seems
like your mama's boy.
Exactly. All right now
our next phrase is when
he was justifying and
say why would I move out?
Why would I leave
my parents house?
I have a great roof over my head
so what does it mean by a great roof?
Okay so the roof means
the top of your house.
You know obviously our house is they're not
open they have a cover and that's called
a roof but the phrase
here a roof over my head
or a roof over one's
head means a place to live.
Okay a home. So if you
say I don't have a roof
over my head that means
I don't have a home I
don't have a house. Okay
so he's saying that he has
a great roof over his head.
His mom does everything
for him so he's like
why would I move out?
And his friend and the conversation by
saying you know what let's agree to disagree.
There's a really
important phrase to learn
especially if you like to
argue a lot in this case
one guy said listen
living at home is good it
works for me and the
other said no it's not very
responsible I agree with
your girlfriend and at the
end they still believe
what they thought originally
so they agree to disagree
that means they're not
going to argue anymore
but they're not going to
change their minds. Right
so I respect your opinion and
you respect my opinion
and the conversation is over.
So Marco chocolate ice cream
is clearly the best ice cream.
Vanilla ice cream is
the best ice cream.
And now I think
chocolate has more flavor.
No vanilla is tastier. Okay
let's agree to disagree.
I still think
chocolate is the best.
Marco still thinks vanilla is the best
but we're not going to argue anymore.
Okay great so let's listen
to her dialogue one last time.
Why did your girlfriend
break up with you?
I don't know she said
she was tired of me not
manning up and being
more independent which I
think is all bunch of
crap. Well you still live
with your parents so
she does have a point.
What do you mean a lot of
people live with their parents
especially when rent
is so expensive in the
slump in the economy?
Yeah but you're almost 40
plus you make good money
so there's really no excuse.
It's just simply because
you're a mama's boy.
Whatever dude I
have everything I need.
Why would I move out? Have
a great roof over my head.
My mom does my
laundry and cooks for me.
What else could a guy ask
for? Let's agree to disagree.
All right so talking about a
mama's boy living at home.
Now as he mentioned
it's well I mean in the
United States kids are
usually leave home when
they're like 18 or 19 when
they go to college right?
But in other places like in Latin America
or even for example in many parts of Europe
people will live at
home until they're 24 or
26 because it is expensive
to live by yourself.
It is and so in a lot of
these countries you you
hear people may be joking
about the men being mama's boys.
Like Italy for example this is often
something that people like to joke about.
Obviously it's not true
in most cases but it is
true that a lot of people
live with their families
until later because like
you say it's expensive
or maybe in their
culture in their tradition
you don't leave your home until you get
married. Right because it could be also for
religious reasons. Exactly and so I think
it differs from culture to culture but this
thing this idea of a mama's
boy is very very much
a part of American culture
we often talk about this.
We often joke about it
and you know sometimes
you say oh you're such
a mama's boy because
you know sometimes
you know like my brother
sometimes like he calls
my mom a lot. So like I say
oh you're such a mama's
boy always calling mom.
No obviously this works
for guys but what about girls.
Would you say like daddy's girl?
Yeah a little bit it's usually
girls who get everything
they want from their dad.
Like daddy I want a new
car daddy I want a new
clothes yeah so daddy's
girl is someone who
is very close with their
dad and maybe is able
to you know have him give
her lots of stuff that she
wants. So but we don't
really hear like like
daddy's boy or a mama's girl
very much right.
It's always opposite.
Yeah yeah exactly. Well it's
a very interesting topic and
well I'm sure many
of you in your different
cultures may also continue
living with your parents
or maybe it's not common
or maybe even after
marriage in many parts
of Asia people get married
and live at home
with their in-laws.
That's right so we're very
curious to hear about your
experience in your
country. Do you have such a
thing as a mama's boy
or a daddy's girl? Let us
know our website is englishpa.com.
All right we'll see you guys there. Bye!